hey what is up everybody Jason here sorry I'm a bit late
as usual things never go according to plan in the JK brickworks
household uh but I think we're all ready to go uh today
we are going to be building the Space Roller Coaster set and
we're going to try and make it move in some way stick
some Motors on it try and make the coaster move on its
own so let's just uh not mess around Jump Right In
uh crack this
open I'm actually really excited to look at some of the new
curved track pieces in this I don't have any of the uh
sloped corner pieces yet so
uh that will be exciting check them out
uh let's see what we got going on here there's some slopes
or tracks there's some tracks who do we got in the chat
R hamburg's in the chat cheers welcome and welcome everybody else
as always just English in the chat so everybody knows what's going
on oh there's bag one two I'll leave
there
three better to actually four
five six
we'll make sure to keep six and nine properly kept track of
since I made that mistake last time instructions we don't need we
got them up on the screen so we are ready to
go this might be a while it'll probably take me I don't
know I probably say an hour and a half or so to
maybe uh build the coaster and then we'll see what we can
do for motorizing it uh all right who do we got in
the chat let's see some regular
faces ah man it's already already
hopping who do we got brook film studio is back cheers welcome
back hi from Germany hello f
f Aubrey
Enzo as4 gaming
cheers hi happy Friday from Poland happy Friday as well my
friend okay here we go one and two we
start building some coasters okay let's just let's just jump right in
well apparently I put one and two
together oh we got a little mini fig little space fig that's
exciting can't have enough little tiny
baby
Spaceman MTH America hey from Hungary cheers hey from Denmark whoop ass
Bill oh he's so cute he's so
cute the little oh little space dude
he's so cute
who doesn't like miniature Lego pieces and then we got some random
dude in a suit of some sort oh he's got funky
hair I don't think I have this hairpiece yet cool oh on
to the good stuff okay we're going to be building a
space roller coaster did everybody see the new set Actually I don't
even know if they were officially announced were they there's a bunch
of new sets coming for 2024 including the Technic
a which actually wasn't too excited about the look of to be
honest um I'm really excited to see all the mechanics they have
in it but uh The Styling I really wish it was more
system instead of Technic
uh well bill just opened the Lego City admin calendar oh we
have the Advent calendar I have not opened it yet today actually
I'll wait till Crystal comes home from work and then we can
open it together uh Enzo hi from Brazil
welcome finish the nine Ranger s oh Mr Sing excellent yes I
just put it together it's on the table as well put in
the mantle I made a little short about it which I just
posted on all social
media that is a uh Staple in our
household cranks little half stud offset cranks love these pieces
I use them all the time for well actually
in the reindeer uses these a lot of these to make the
reindeer Gallop it's a great way to get just really subtle motion
instead of you [Music] know normally when
you build a crank with normal Technic pieces the range of motion
is you know at least a full stud but or two studs
but uh with this you can make a nice little half
stud offset on the radius anyway
uh okay I'm looking for Technic connector oh there
it is well there it
is uh nothing can beat the cat one yeah the a uh
I actually do like the look of the cat one much better
I mean I may be a little bit biased in that but
uh I do love I do like the look of the brickbuilt
planets better than the like the big just curve round Sun
I haven't taken a really really close look at it cuz I
mean I'm going to get it obviously and uh build it on
stream at some point I don't even know when it comes out
but
uh but I don't really like the ah yeah I just don't
really I'm not really a big fan of the look over look
of it yes please don't spell what was in the Advent calendar
today uh what T today today we have actually I haven't even
tasted yet I just pulled a random bag out of the box
it's a fruity tea for sure I think it's wild I think
it's wild berry just random mix of
berries Victor hi from Poland
cheers uh can you say what the weather status it is sunny
out actually I'm like 4° C uh which
is pretty warm for this time of year here for December 1st
I will take it hopefully Crystal I actually we're going to the
climbing gym when Crystal gets home okay here we have a little
crankshaft which is cool I am a big fan of
crankshafts let's see what we get putting onto
this
I claim to build a roller coaster and little did I know
I am going to be building
some uh automat we're going to build some kinetic
movement everybody's a big fan why is this move so slow oh
I rammed
that I feel like there's a lot of friction in this for
some
reason anyway okay we will see okay
uh but we're making a little piston here which is really
cool I do love myself a good PR piston Mr Sing bought
two of these Space sets in order to build all three models
o yeah I actually to be honest I haven't even really looked
at the other models for this three in one uh
I'll take a look at the instructions after I'm done with
this maybe there's some other possibilities for motor
motorization and
such from all my models the cata solar system is the set
everyone finds interesting our Hamburg yeah I mean it is a pretty
interesting set Crystal uses it all the time for science
class every year when she does the uh her teaching module on
you know the solar system she makes them watch the a video
which is a bit crazy um and uh
you know it's pretty I mean obviously it's not completely accurate but
uh it's pretty pretty good illustration about how the
uh Earth and the moon
rotate oh man Milo yesterday was minus 13 here in Sweden whoa
yeah it's chil it's coming to Canada too well at least at
my part part of Canada for sure
uh it's coming I'm enjoying the warm weather while it
lasts ja hey I'm watching with my two sons 4 and six
Frank and Johnny yeah if you can say hello to them hey
how's it going we're in
Poland huge fan of Lego yeah who isn't a huge fan of
Lego okay uh well welcome to the stream
hopefully you're building cool stuff it is the season
to enjoy Lego even more I think once Christmas comes
if you celebrate Christmas that is or whatever holidays you happen to
uh celebrate this time of year uh
okay we're building a little shuttle it's pretty cool I need a
round one by one
really what is that I'll add that later
I'm sure it'll come out in the
wash
white cheese slopes minus 11 in Germany yesterday whoa
also too
chil when motorizing mocks is heat a concern could fully enclosed LEGO
motor overheat while running for prolonged periods of time uh
yeah I mean Motors definitely wear out if you're running them for
like a full
day it depends on a lot of factors how much
uh stress their load they put under I know like the GBC
guys go through Motors pretty often you know motor might last for
like a full few- day event but uh I mean actually that
being said I have not ever burnt out
a what any of my Motors yet actually but I don't really
run things for most things for a very long period of
time and most of the stuff I build isn't put doesn't put
the motors under a lot of
stress little space mini pig mini space
dude oh I see this goes on
here oh yeah that's cool that's cool we got a little little
space
ride it's very unpredictable but uh actually works really
well a little floppy that is
cool okay now we are on to building the
base of the coaster I assume
oh Jacob bought this for my son for Christmas oh that's awesome
it'll be a great Christmas
present oh my gosh our hamburg's car wi start yesterday that's
unfortunate and in Brazil it's too hot to even go in the
car
yeah
could tell a bit more about circuit cubes how many do you
have
uh circuit cubes yeah I mean they're pretty awesome I have uh
what do I have I think I have like three or four
Cubit Motors and maybe a couple of battery boxes
all you really need is the all I ever use are the
Cubit Motors so they're like that clear like transparent uh
2x4 brick ones bit they're like two 2x4 bricks tall I
think Cubit motor and then the Bluetooth battery box is uh what
I use although you can use the standard battery box
too and obviously you need a wire to connect them which I
believe should come with whatever you buy I don't even remember anymore
but okay I assume these are all the same cuz Lego
is like that make sure I put that one stud off
yep uh do anyone do the Lego Star Wars ad
encounter I don't have the Star Wars one this year actually I
might oh I should see if uh might try and pick up
the Marvel one actually I don't think I've ever built
a Marvel admin calendar I have the we have the city one
right now but the more of the
marer oh hello from India did I buy anything on Black Friday
actually you know what I never did I very tempted there were
like tons of sales in North America like the lion Knights Castle
was 25% off but I restrained myself I
knew realistically that they would just kind of if I bought
stuff especially big sets like that I just would never build it
anyway
so I was very proud of myself for showing restraint
oh my God G Jacobson when he worked outside all the time
anything above minus 17 was warm yeah I mean it's all relative
to what you're used to I
guess the human body can put up with a lot of stress
if
needed
okay we're getting
uh a lot of basic brick in
this make a nice secure
stand which I guess is
smart well Eric's got the friends
calendar for the animals oh yeah cuz it was on special
I don't know if I ever if I've ever had the friends
calendar man it's definitely a good basic brick parts pack jeez got
tons of uh 2x6
bricks
oh I definitely forgot some pieces at the top here
there we go good to go back on track well our
Hamburg bought a huge Star Wars ship saved 80
cool well indie has the Star Wars Advent calendar cheers
awesome uh what are we building we were building the Space 3
in1 roller coaster and then we're going to stick a motor on
it somehow or some Motors on
it we're going to see if we can actually get it to
run on its own
cuz nobody wants to play with things by hand anymore I me
come
on actually I'm super I'm sure it's super fun to play with
uh just pushing it around with your hand as well but
uh I'm a big fan of uh you know seeing
what's possible
obviously in terms of motorization and automation so that is what we're
going to do Daniel which Motors will you use and will you
use Mindstorms no I think I'm just for this video actually I
was thinking about how I could integrate mind storms into this system
but for this video I think I'm just going to stick some
power functions on it we're just going to run it
continuously but I was thinking for like a layout of some
sort you could definitely use mind storms to like stop and start
the whatever you have running on the roller coaster track that way
if you had some kind of like City transport
system a trolley or something that you had on the roller coaster
track you could uh have it run intermittently which would be pretty
cool I
think well that is clearly not the way that goes
uh I need another one of
these green 2x2 jumper plate looks
cool weird cool weird color yeah it's like bright
green uh is this Lego set of element stores yeah it actually
came out relatively recently it's pretty new uh so yeah it should
be available unless it's sold
out all right we need two of
these yes please no
spamming what made you get interested in Lego
uh well like most kids I was uh probably a gift from
my parents when I was
young that's how I started building was a long long time
ago of course I put that in the wrong
spot
forklift yeah actually it probably wasn't the very first set I got
I think the first set we got was probably just Universal building
blocks just one of the like basic sets
um and then maybe I got some
space sets after that
classic space and then eventually the Technic forklift
which yeah I keep uh I keep forgetting I need to add
that to like a I need to somehow get the parts for
that so we can build it on stream that would be a
cool Retro Retro build
stream any suggestions of how to get in the mock building
well first you need some pieces for one thing take some sets
apart I mean actually the crater 3 in one sets would be
a great start for that just pick up a small one
Whatever theme you're interested in you know and just see what else
you can build using it I mean it might not be very
pretty or anything don't worry don't even worry about that but just
uh you know start putting bricks together and seeing what you can
do
the other strategy is just to uh you could use
Studio to build things digitally uh if you don't have a lot
of pieces on hand or you don't want to take a set
apart I don't know just start start building
walls Britney Campbell is this your first live video no definitely not
uh you already built with the basic bricks
box is that a question for me I have no
idea ever thought of doing like stop motion Lego oh my gosh
my friend yes I have done stop motion Lego what you don't
you don't remember the stop motion videos I made 20 years ago
very
disappointed actually my friend Dean and I had a very popular one
back in the day probably over 20 years ago
now but uh no I have no interest in doing stop motion
anymore it's just way way too much
work I mean maybe at some point I might play around with
it again but I doubt it I really don't have
time I'd rather design new models to be
honest
okay our frame is coming along coming along
well big gray frame everybody
loves everybody loves
that there saw I'm sorry for not seeing I will find it
Lego Battle Master oh no don't be sorry that was like 20
years ago my friend uh it's also not on this channel it's
on my secondary Channel if you search for the rescue
uh I mean it's terrible by today's standards it's like really low
res I actually use some software to upsample it
I think I we originally shot it in like 240
uh like 320 by 240 like super low Reds because at the
time this was 20 years ago remember we had just a crappy
web camera uh to do
it haa stand in the
corner
uh how many subscribers I have I mean you can just look
that up quite
easily I Believe YouTube tells you right at the top
somewhere uh okay oh
interesting why am I missing did I put an
extra one of those somewhere that I wasn't supposed to Palisade
brick is it in the
bag I bet I'm just going to get a new
one nobody hunts for bricks when I can just jump to the
collection uh yeah g Jacobson has got a good suggestion bu used
Lego lot watch YouTube video experiment with Lego connections and get creative
that's my advice yep yeah I mean I think
a lot of times inspiration just comes from like randomly putting pieces
together you know just see see what you can do let's build
some table scraps that's what we call them when you're just like
playing around with pieces and seeing what happens
well I guess we need
some roller coaster
track oh I hate it when Lego says have missing pizzas as
well I wish all my Lego sets came with
pizza
but yeah no that's terrible when they actually come with I mean
I don't know if this is actually a missing piece that could
have just might still be in the bag or something but yeah
it' be super annoying if it was actually missing a [Music]
piece well that's a I need a regular
curved yeah so actually these uh sloped curved rails
these are the first ones
first ones I have which are pretty cool it's an interesting piece
you can make some like spiral Spiral
thingies
uh did you build the melan Falcon from the Valentine's oh no
I never did I still have the original melan Falon in a
box uh
I doubt I will ever build it to be
honest Milo I've W Lego Power functions mode in a battery box
but the battery box got damaged oh that
sucks that is a shame oops I jumped ahead whoa
whoa where am I here okay oh now we get to build
what I can only assume is the Earth
or at least some kind of
planet get some round dishes
o on boat stud these
funky the they're kind of
semi-transparent or translucent very vaguely but like kind of
shimmery
metallic I don't think I have anything in this color it's
cool I see we get to stick this on the side some
random Planet that's
cool that is
cool I missed the dark ray cheese wedges on the small stand
yeah
probably that'll happen oh there's the nose of the
spaceship dark wedge oh yeah there it is dark wedge
dark gray wedge cheese slope there we go
excellent and what else we got here a little flag
exploration flag somebody dropped on the train oh yeah I
see I assume these are
Footprints somebody Footprints leading to a flag that's cool it's a nice
little
detail oh there's the missing piece thanks good eye good eye my
friend okay that's it for bag number number
one and two so now we need three and four
[Music]
have I heard what Lego is doing to that small store you
no I have not heard anything about
that I got a duplicate in my Harry Potter admin calendar last
year oo the drel and Owl but
miss the owy that's
unfortunate
how much do this Lego set I have no idea to be
honest I can't
remember 120 Canadian maybe 130 Canadian I don't know maybe
100 bucks [Music]
us we need a monreal
remake yeah I believe that ship is sailed okay hey
we got some space [Music]
people excellent some scientists
an astronaut in full get up
where my heads where my heads at
it's cool it's quite the elaborate
outfit
I guess we'll just give her hair for
now little Command Center woman little astronaut
[Music]
lady that is cool where my legs
at I'm sure I'll find them
okay
on
to part
two
uh Milo has built a moving tank with the motor in it
but yeah since the B box is broken that's less useful for
sure have a little ladder it's important for the Minifigs to have
ways to get around t my friend actually I don't drink
coffee I never ever really started to be honest and
uh
yeah apparently I don't need
it okay uh we have some random
propeller I don't know what that's all about
it's on a friction pin so you can't even spin it oh
you can't spin it interesting oh because
the the pin Joiner is on a non-f friction pin at the
bottom
excellent well now I think we're building some kind of Command
Module oh yeah there's the white legs good eye
10:35 a.m. here in Michigan us yes same time as I am
eastern time Canada or
us
okay lot of useful white
pieces after building the ski hill I've had my feel of building
with white the ski hill and the Sant the reindeer there's
a lot of
white but uh yeah this looks pretty cool cool so
far oh was a Turn Style I see
that makes sense to get on the ride I guess it
is and here I was thinking it was some kind of realistic
uh space uh Outpost or something but I guess really it's just
an amusement park
ride
this must be the
entrance slash Command
Module or maybe the gift
shop
bartender have you thought about building your own Lego
Clock uh yeah I mean I was thinking about it back in
I mean I built a I built the ball clock 15 years
ago actually it's like the first video I ever made that went
viral was the ball clock back in the day
mind you it doesn't keep any accurate time but uh you know
okay uh and then uh yeah every once in a while I
think about building a clock but I feel like a lot of
people have built clocks over the years so I don't think I
really there's anything I can really add to
the putting on backwards obviously because that's what I do
there we
go well allergies are kicking
in oh my God it's the problem with living in this place
in
winter
staying inside all the time there's so much
dust the allergies hit
okay this is kind of a funky little building we have like
inner doors curved walls like what's that
about we can't even really like get inside
to to
play it's definitely sparsely decorated as
well uh G Jacobson your ball clock was a cool build oh
cheers thanks really appreciate
that bless me thank you very much allergic to Lego actually
I do think uh maybe not the Lego but all the like
Storage Solutions and stuff I have in here some of the plastic
I'm sure is not very like healthy all the off Casas
thing
it is probably not the greatest environment to be constantly exposed to
24/7 I always feel so much better when we're traveling in the
summer but it's hard to tell if that's like environmental cuz we
spend a lot of time in the desert which in general is
much better for if you have allergies and stuff than Ottawa
at least anyway there's just too many things growing
here okay we got some other see some Technic things going on
here do we get some other kind of
uh things that move oh maybe not
what are we building
here some kind of Hydroponics green and blue
something must be
living how do you prevent your builds from collecting dust usually I
don't have them on display they usually live in boxes actually there's
there's stuff like on the shelf behind me and on this shelf
over here they're pretty dusty now but uh all the all the
models I have on display upstairs are in a glass cabinet so
that helps a lot and then uh a lot of the stuff
I'm working on is in a actually you might be able to
see it yeah this cabinet here has doors on it so this
is where I store a lot of Works in progress or models
that I set aside for a little while or even models that
are finished that just need a place to go and uh that's
definitely a good way to keep the dust off them and then
a lot of stuff just lives in
boxes
okay uh where does this go opposite flag
looks like some kind of air locky thing it's interesting we put
all those trans clear uh bricks inside and we don't even get
to see
them o Super Chat from hosan cheers
thanks very much appreciated loves my videos
that's uh that's awesome thanks so much for the
donation bartender oh yes the ball clock very nice not seen it
before yeah it's pretty
old uh in France here we do have a great thing like
Lego but not that
big Dr magic must have patience to do all this construction uh
yeah obviously it takes a little while
um but uh a lot of people find it therapeutic it's calming
and relaxing it's very satisfying to put pieces
together it's also real really satisfying when you start building your own
models to when they finally come together sometimes it can be
frustrating when things don't work out but uh uh
what do we got with this guy each one of these is
slightly
different oo portal
gold uh do you get neck back pain from building for too
long oh AR now gets it uh
whoa Planet just went flying in general no because I
do when I'm building normally I do walk around a lot to
go get parts and stuff when I'm live streaming actually sometimes
my back gets a little sore because I'm not cuz I'm just
standing in the same place pretty much the entire time wow I
mean if I'm only doing like an hour or an hour and
a half live stream it's fine but when I do a three-hour
live stream it does get a little hard on the
body man I love these curved pieces you can make some
nice cool smooth shaping these days with Lego
oh this is definitely some kind of hydroponic
Bay we have some soil and what I
assume will be some kind of plants that's
cool we definitely need to make food to feed the
astronauts
do you build standing up yes I'm standing up right now
and actually yeah I do have a desk over there it's actually
standup convertible sit down standup desk but I don't actually use it
anymore it's just full of crap right
now uh where will you put it after where will put this
uh probably just take it apart to be honest
uh I have I made recommendation for your channel to a person
from another country oh cheers thanks much appreciated o deep deep my
videos are so satisfying yeah the shorts
are seem to be quite popular oh we got our little
Greenhouse at the top super
cool
uh I have a Star Wars X-Wing to build but I'm afraid
to lose a piece well yeah you definitely want to be an
environment where you don't lose pieces losing pieces is
uh undesirable for
sure oh yes that's cool got a little
hatch for our for our Greenhouse
well very nice I love the style of the top of this
it's really cool
design do I build standing up yes I am I'm standing up
uh nothing better than the new brick smell when you open a
new Lego set yeah it is pretty nice
uh where are you based I am in Canada
Ottawa uh congrats on my work cheers thanks much appreciated
uh do you ever wish to go back in time to Toys
R Us and just get all those medieval sets in blue coat
sets for
cheap
yeah I mean there are definitely some cool classic sets that would
be nice to go back and get some of but uh
sadly that ship is
sailed in each pack you have an explication I'm not sure what
you're saying there uh how do you feel about too many new
specialized pieces or now yeah uh well that does not go
there yeah I'm definitely not a fan of specialized pieces I am
a fan of like new pieces that kind of complete the system
um but yeah you know it is what it is I mean
Lego is definitely pumping out new pieces like crazy these days
uh it almost seems a bit overwhelming sometimes because there's just uh
so many new pieces to keep track
of get some Rando antennas that's cool little antenna array that's that's
pretty awesome communication is
key in every space
station
cool getting there five and
six not five and
nine wow it's huge yeah this set is actually quite big I
was uh
I was uh a little concerned about whether I I have to
raise this this camera up quite a bit in anticipation I still
don't know if I'll get it all in frame uh but we'll
see Dr magic went to Canada a long time ago it is
quite a nice country uh it's a very big country there is
a
lot there is a lot to it okay yeah I think we
only I think we've only buildt like half of the coaster layout
I think there's like a whole other loop on this side so
which I guess we're building the base of
now so yeah this thing is going to be quite
large hey what's up
yerb not much we're building a space coaster
let me organize some of these
pieces this Technic really difficult for a first-time Builder I never had
time Lego as a kid yeah I actually I would depends what
Technic set you get I think some of the big Flagship Technic
sets are actually quite complicated um I mean I think the instructions
are quite good but you I think in for some of them
you do have to kind of pay attention to what's going
on with system builds you can kind of like pay half attention
and you know whatever if you forget if you miss a piece
or something it's usually not critical you can usually fix it later
or you can just like it'll be okay if you just leave
it out but but in Technic builds if you get something slightly
off or get something wrong especially with like complex gear systems uh
sometimes it's really hard to recover from mistakes and if you have
to go back and like pull things apart it's Can it can
be quite
cumbersome so yeah I think you General you do have to pay
attention a little bit more whereas for this build for example I'm
just kind of like like throwing the pieces on and if something
gets put in the wrong spot
well it'll be
okay o random Technic bricks what are we going to be doing
with these I
wonder
uh
let see did I do that
interesting it's like the they have different pins oh
cuz I didn't put all the pins in I need another
pin there we go two black pins two gray
pins
oh my gosh then of course putting
helps if you put the mole on one side first and then
put the thing on all right there we
go what's your favorite plant plant piece oh I
actually do really like the new Fern piece
big fan of the new Fern piece I got to say uh
but actually these pieces are really cool too actually I do like
this piece very
nice but the fern one might be my new favorite
uh yeah and maybe followed by this
one
okay man there definitely very lot of steps in
this don't want to put too many pieces on at the same
time sometimes I think they could put just a few more steps
a few more pieces for First Step people figured
[Music]
out okay I'm already
uh running low on Space here keyboard's got to go up
out of
way okay sorry again little behind on the
chat as usual that's a four by 2x4 first oh no I
already put two
before uh what time is it here it's almost 11 o'clock in
the
morning uh personal feel like old more angular Lego sets have certain
charm to them yeah for sure
I mean it's a balance between having it look like Lego and
you know like the new Spider-Man bus that was just released it
it almost looks like a little uncanny cuz it's it's
like almost close to being a like hyper realistic
it's too it's like too realistic it's less
legoy
uh yeah Cy new sets with all the special pieces don't even
look like Lego sometimes yeah
uh should I ask for a place made up for Lego construction
in my future house yes obviously everybody needs a Lego build
room
uh yeah there's not many small Lego Technic pieces or sets
I
guess I guess once you're like into Technic you just want the
flagship
models what is that like gray like
gray did you ever build the Apple Tower no have zero interest
in building the Apple Tower it see seems very
like whoops those are definitely the wrong color it seems like
a thoroughly unpleasant build to be
honest would you find reading the instructions for the Lego sets that
they came with easier or did you find it easier to look
it up on the internet and do it from there uh I
don't know I think it depends
on what kind of experience you
like if I'm sitting down at a table to build I would
definitely just use the instructions that come with the
set because uh I think it's a much nicer building experience but
if I'm I'm at the computer and I have the computer on
uh I mean this
is this isn't uh
any more difficult than using the paper
instructions but it depends on a lot of things like how good
your screen
is if I was sitting at a table I definitely would not
use a tablet or
anything okay I think we're we're getting close to finishing the
the framing for the base is actually super solid which I guess
it has to
be uh did I finish that
yeah uh such a such of the well some of the big
sets can be bor boring to build there's much repetition yeah for
sure yeah like some of them I have like zero interest in
the a tower for one the Coliseum looks kind of dull the
captain Shield oh my gosh that looks absolutely terrible to build
uh or Captain America
shield but sometimes that's just uh you know necessary
evil to get something that looks good I mean certainly I've designed
my own models that are very repetitive I mean the Domino machine
is the Domino ring is absolutely terrible to build
you have to build like 64 of all the Domino stands and
everything oh my God it was such a slug to put that
thing
together sometimes that's the that's the only way to build it is
to okay we got an eyeball some kind of alien happening over
here every good space set needs a some kind of alien alien
life how are you going to motorize this are you going to
use a chain left no I think this set the small sets
uh I kind of prototyped some stuff it's like
too much work I think to implement a chain into like a
the small coaster set so I designed like uh some kind of
a flywheel accelerator system that uh you can tack onto the
side at least that's what I prototyped anyway we'll uh we'll see
how well it works
we will get to that once uh once the build is
finished and then it'll either work or it won't hopefully it won't
take too long to find
out
two of these then one of those
excellent It's Lego moving away from base plates yeah I mean they've
been well I think the only things that use base plates anymore
are the Modular Buildings uh so
yeah do you already know how to motorize this yeah I have
a pretty good idea the motor will be on the track no
I'm not going to motorize the actual like physical roller coaster
it's like too small uh sometimes find myself buying sets
for parts yeah I mean I do that all the
time in fact that's mostly why I buy sets is just to
get
parts actually I guess that's not true anymore back in the day
it certainly
was it's not a very good way to get parts unless you're
buying certain like I think this set is a good set to
get parts wow you get a lot of basic bricks and plates
which are Super
handy oh and we have a little mounted camera that's
cool but of course it's facing away from the alien that's coming
out of the system super
cool that's pretty cool little alien I got to see you always
got to watch out for
aliens invading your
space
uh bashy hey Jay just thanks so much for making the maze
oh cheers old school throwback it's a set that means a lot
to me and it's still my favorite set I own oh that's
awesome yeah I was uh super surprised that I actually got selected
back in the day I don't think they would make it anymore
there's too many other good uh Lego idea
sets have you seen the new tech Technic Space sets yeah yeah
I have I'm not as I mentioned at the beginning of this
uh I'm not super excited about the look of Yi but uh
you know
whatever that's why I built my
own uh fly wheels to push it up or will it be
fullon launch coaster yeah I mean I think we can play around
with that I don't think it Mo will move fast enough to
like launch the coaster up the hill but uh
yeah basically it'll just push the coaster up
the up the slopes hopefully
these angled curved slopes will be a little bit of a challenge
so excuse me we'll see we'll see how it
goes okay we got another support
excellent and even more support
s oh Dr mag got to go cheers thanks for
joining love to see you build a custom ghost train style build
from a Fairground oh yeah surprising haven't made a set for that
one yet oh yeah I mean that's a great idea I mean
they've built a ghost train in the past so maybe it's coming
I mean they can't build everything at once
so sometimes they got to spread it out a little
bit okay that's clearly a good support Oo we got some more
coaster [Music] pieces here is an uphill or a downhill
who knows oh I clearly forgot to I supposed to put two
oh yeah where's my other uphill there it
is okay now we're getting
some some height where do all these glow-in-the-dark pieces go
I guess they're
coming
I got to go turn the heater
off starting to get a little
hot you miss the challenge of building with your very limited number
of Parts H like most of us morals yeah but
the beautiful thing especially about like crater 3 in one sets is
that if I ever want to feel like I want to build
something with limited parts I just bust open a crater 3 in
one set and I just see what I can build with just
using the parts in that set which is a great way to
to force yourself to build from a limited parts pallet
again haven't done that in a while actually I guess the last
time was
the uh was the bricks and functions set which I guess actually
wasn't that long ago
but yeah it's a great way to exercise
creativity fornal liked every one of my short videos cheers
thanks uh idea when the new Lego cata set will be released
I have no clue no I haven't heard from them in a
while uh okay what do we got here I think we get
a new bag s and eight
I think this is it for the for the actual coaster
base isn't this a three in one set yeah it is it
is a three in one set maybe I'll see if I can
build something else with
it
crazy Turtle really enjoys my builds
cheers that is much
appreciated oh I have to put my turntables together myself that's a
relatively new thing LEGO has been doing hope if I did it
the right
way oh no what the the H did I do I jumped
ahead too much oh burnt orange
tiles that's cool I like this color
actually as
well Al little the burnt orange against the regular orange is a
little bit of a clashes a
bit
okay what are we building here some kind of crazy vehicle
of some
sort one by one rounds as Wheels that's pretty interesting
like micro scale Rover of some
sort it's
fun ah Corner plate where or where is my corner
plate oh there it is I see it I see
it oo trans orange 4x4 Corner
tiles
it's definitely some kind of little Rover oh yeah it's like a
Curiosity Rover it's even got a little camera mounted
on the
top where is I need a pearl
gold telescope where the heck is
that hiding
somewhere oh there it
is there it
is
okay okay okay okay we got oh I see the rover
sits on a turntable oh yeah it's digging up the terrain I
guess the Orange is supposed to be kind of like Mars
I
guess I see we're supporting the
upper section of the coaster here so we're going to add some
axles for stability
so when I put these stanions up I assume it will
be
relatively
strong
I think that's it for that yeah okay
uh yeah and now yeah we are
building some platforms which I
assume The Coasters will go
on support the track piece
the track pieces need your
support oh there's my
bracket
okay
is this table connected with the legs the studio video it looked
like just put it on top Loosely yeah
uh the legs those legs flimsy legs are gone this table now
sits on cabinets basically I have cabinets underneath but
uh the top is just loose this is a 4T
by 8T sheet of well laminated plywood basically
or press board or something and yeah it just sits Loosely on
top of the cabinets underneath it I mean it's so
heavy it's definitely not moving very
easily the original legs I had it on the original leg frame
they were pretty flimsy actually they did not
hold up super well
o we have a flexible
rubber lift arm thing I wonder what that's
for I do like this piece actually this like flexible rubber one
it's comes in very handy in some situations I don't know what
they're doing using it for
this piece but
uh one two
three
getting some big
stands if we look from the side yeah we're definitely getting some
height we ever nled the pieces before building a set no
uh definitely not not uh super organized anyway I mean sometimes I
try and separate pieces out
roughly uh but definitely not three I need three of these where
the heck's the other one go one two oh back
here perspective is a little odd on this angle
okay what color is that that is black there it
is oh and a gray one interesting odd that they put
one of each color in it seems a little
unnecessary what seven long
axle
okay where does this one
go
uh oh Joko is back hey I'm trying to
get involved with the Lego Community how are you guys uh we're
great build my Space Coaster Alpine versus Nordic skiing skating versus
classic style
uh I mean I used to ski Alpine Ski quite a bit
back in the day and then I used to snowboard quite a
bit back in the day as well as well but lately definitely
Nordic skiing it's just so much easier we can actually just go
like right outside our house just there's Trails down by the river
in the winter that are uh even groomed
uh like 500 meters from our house so that's pretty awesome
and then Ottawa has a ton of Nordic skiing trails in the
area so yeah I definitely PR it's cheap it's
easy it's good the Alpine skiing around here is not that great
eastern Ontario is it's like East Coast Canada it's like too
icy it's not like the west
coast and uh we usually just do classic
style is the entire basement for your Lego area Yep this whole
room in the Bas basement which is
like I can't remember how big it is 4 M by 7
m
no yeah something like that seven yeah I think it's 4X 8
m this whole
room it is entirely for
Lego why do you not use a chair cuz I like standing
especially when I'm building my own models uh I go like collect
parts so often if I was sitting it's actually really annoying because
you got to get up every time you have to get up
out of the chair go get parts come back sit down then
just do it again in like 30 seconds so
uh so yeah that's why I usually build standing
up
got some kind of doohickey going on here I don't know what
this is but it looks like it moves and it might do
something fun let's hope
so know why we didn't build this while we were building the
stand it would have been a lot more stable but whatever o
and we got a little coaster piece on the
top oh and then we got some
Flames got some Flames [Music]
happening looking forward to how you motorize this yeah what' I say
at the beginning it would be like an hour and a half
to build this so we're getting close maybe a little more than
an hour and a half to build the
set an hour and a half to two hours to build a
set and then hopefully the motorizing won't take that
long I'm sure we can get it up and running in like
half an
hour clearly some kind of comment oh that's
cool I don't know how this is going to get activated but
uh we have some kind of I bet when the roller coaster
comes past it like pushes it
up I do love me some Play
features
how many of these do I need
six one two three four five
six
interesting
oh and we finally finish
off putting all the coaster pieces
on
excellent hopefully it all lines up we did this
right oh yes it works
excellent and then we tile these connections all
up
and then we put some random lights on everybody needs some
[Music]
random
detailing do you like kaying actually no I never really got into
kayaking
much I'm actually not much of a water sports kind of guy
I don't SW I don't swim very well so
uh excuse me I'm too skinny I sink
uh so yeah I've never really well that's the other
clip where the heck does that go oh I see it goes
under
there so yeah I never never really got into many water sports
which is a shame because uh they do look pretty
fun but there's only so much one can do in life and
since we spend so much time rock climbing uh that is definitely
takes up most of our time we got ourselves a light
brick which is pretty exciting
everybody loves getting a light
Breck oh I love it when sets has surprise feature one didn't
know about yeah yeah I didn't look uh I didn't look into
this set at all in terms of uh that's cool the light
we put a hole right in front of the light yeah I
didn't look at any reviews for this set or anything uh so
I really have no idea what
uh what this set will I don't even know what it like
looks like when it's when it's going or how the coaster travels
very I mean I assume it goes around the coaster track obviously
but uh I have no
pre know pre-known knowledge about this set okay
here we have some kind of blinking light thing o and we
have like a big crater on the back of
it to activate it some kind of Rocky
feature oh North Carolina in house JD how could I find Lego
communities in my area uh I believe there are resources to do
that I'm pretty sure somewhere on the Lego website
H it's probably not the main Lego website there is a
list of all the Lego
clubs in the world uh but I'm sure Google is your friend
I'm sure you can just search online I mean I assume you've
tried to look for North Carolina Lego user group that would be
the first thing I would
do oo Flames oh again this is like a larger version
of this Comet oh man it's cool we got
some
Flamin we need to turn the lights off
except my uh
Auto there we
go cool that's
fun where does this go this goes
here
say tax on the side it's a shame that this doesn't activate
by the coaster moving or maybe it does I have no
idea we'll see I guess either way it's pretty
fun everybody loves light up features
isn't that Sac religion canot to go kayaking or canoeing I mean
we canoe I own a canoe Crystal I own a canoe so
yes we go canoeing quite often it's definitely a very Canadian to
co canoeing uh not kayaking though although a lot of people do
kayak
but uh yeah so yes we definitely have a canoe
uh it is sacrilege to not skate though skating is definitely more
of a Canadian
thing but uh I can't say I skate all that great I
never actually played hockey when I was a kid but uh but
I can actually skate so all hope it's not
lost those light bricks remind me of the old RC X touch
sensors yeah they are very similar form
factor the way you talk about Lego sometimes feels like a love
hate relationship yeah I mean it's just like any relationship
there's highs and there's lows there's good and there's bad you
never really know it's a very flexible thing I have
no idea why I have
one Technic connector left over okay here we
have a little ringed planet of some sort I guess that's
what this
is it's cool okay clearly I like oh I forgot
to put these on so that's why those exist oh
also forgot to put one of these tiles on oh my gosh
everything all over place that's probably I mean this shouldn't be an
extra piece where the heck did this come from oh that goes
on the comet clearly forgot that no idea where that goes
that's probably extra extra extra extra extra extra extra extra this should
not be extra i' oh this and this probably oh I forgot
the oh this should be higher
yeah just uh okay finally on the bag nine which is the
last
bag uh awesome fire forgot the orange slope yep thanks I've eventually
figured that out took me a while
uh
looks amazing yeah it's coming together pretty nice actually I do like
uh a lot of the all the details and
everything but I assume we finally get some coasters yeah oh yeah
they actually need Wheels in
them guess I have to put them
together uh oh and we clearly have some kids who
are going to enjoy the the ride how much did you
get this for I mean I just paid full price for it
cuz I knew I wanted it and I wanted to build it
and motorize it so and I wanted it sooner rather than
later oh they have cute little classic
space printing on them that's so
cute that's so cute
like short little stubby
legs pigtails everybody likes the
pigtails I don't know where the heck the other head went well
there's the hair oh the head is already on oh my gosh
I'm losing my
mind okay mini figs are sorted all done
with oo looks like we're building some kind of
Rocket Saturn five Style it's very American
styling snore subscribed I'm in love a
cheers uh holda I wish oh I wish I had a two
un broke yeah I mean sad sadly Lego is expensive there's no
getting around
that all Hammer glad I didn't into getting a crappy set yeah
oh I knew it was going to be
good I mean you can tell just by the photos it's uh
going be a pretty nice
set and lately the crater 3 in one sets have all been
pretty decent in my
opinion o friction half pins I do love friction half pins
definitely bought a fair number of these already from
uh Lego online pick a
Breck palade priest really extra no no I miss I quote unquote
lost this as I was building and I fetched another one from
my Lego collection and then I eventually found
it Lego's really into space now with all these new Technic sets
yeah yeah the Technic lineup looks pretty interesting actually I don't know
if I'll buy I mean I'll buy the a
obviously uh the Rover kind of looks pretty cool too
I might pick that up but you know I probably don't need
it so maybe if it goes on sale the gray
wheels look pretty interesting
though I haven't taken a I didn't have a chance yet to
really take a good look at the photos uh but I probably
will at some
point I'm sure some other fan sites will do a breakdown of
uh
oh I put that on backwards so you know put that on
the wrong side that goes on the top oh it's
quite a substantial rocket
actually get some more Flames at the back oh you couldn't give
me four Flames I only get two
flames
where does this oh this rocket goes
on angled excellent that's
cool man it's shaping up to be pretty big but
uh cool little rocket
excellent
uh I've got a wild idea for you take the new UCS
at8 and find a way to motorize it to walk like the
old Technic
atat
yeah uh I had I was planning to
uh
build a walking atat at some point before they released the UCS
atat and uh just never really came
about but yeah I have no interest in buying
the the UCS one this is too big for
for me o we got some lettering that's cool dot Style
that's a pretty nice little font they have here two
by three studs can we get all
the letters to look
good getting them to all be like super straight might be a
little bit annoying but
uh what's it going to say who knows it'll
be a
surprise Oh missing antenna on top oh yeah clearly
spaceship is missing an antenna think of
it as
investment yeah okay we got to deal with the antenna on top
of the spaceship there we go or I guess it's a rocket
it's not really a
ship okay we got
Spa what could possibly be the next letter I don't
know I guess I should actually look at the instructions I'm just
kind of building the letters the way I think they should go
together which uh I assume is the way they'll do
it oh it's pretty nice font actually they're lucky
that all these letters can be done very easily in a 3X
two it gets a little dicey when you have to make something
like an
M there just not enough two studs wide is not big enough
for for like an
M cool space that's pretty
awesome
well I guess I'm doing things a bit out of order as
usual okay uh I think I got this some good
got our space Oh what do I do with this oh let's
see don't do anything with it
yet
uh oh order the k for S shark waiting for it to
arrive looking forward to building it oh yeah might it might be
a while depending on when you ordered it uh they're like so
swamped with orders uh it's a bit crazy to be
honest okay and here we have oh are we finally building
part of the coaster I think we might be
this might be the actual
coaster oh oh no this is just the rocket for
the it's cool we have like a shuttle that's pretty awesome
actually and two little Flames at the
back
how does this go there we go oh man that's
uh it's actually quite nice little space logo
with
the the little shuttle in the middle it's pretty cool super cool
actually actually where does this go this goes
here
space
awesome awesome okay we're definitely once I get
the instructions out of the way we'll actually be able to see
this in full uh but uh for now we just got
to imagine controversial opinion I don't like plastic
bags yeah I mean nobody likes plastic bags I don't think that's
controversial it's pretty wasteful okay finally get to build the
coaster cardboard trays I mean they're going to plast or paper bags
but uh have yet to actually get any paper bags it's been
a long process and I still don't think they're actually 100% paper
I think they're lined with like uh film so so
I don't know how recyclable they actually are the old Technic at
was the first motorized set I ever got oh wow still have
it in storage you know I never got that one actually was
pretty amazing yeah which is why I wanted to design my own
I speak Spanish there's no question mark there so that's a statement
but no I don't
uh what do you think about the new speed Champion sets uh
I mean I just had a quick glance at at them I
didn't really take a good look so I have no not formed
an opinion yet I mean on first very quick glance they look
pretty
good oo Jeffrey ordered three sets on Monday and they're coming
today lucky
you uh what is that
gray 1 by two plate okay we're finally building a
coaster with some streamlined sides on it excellent
hello welcome to the chat space sign is pretty sweet space sign
is amazing it is uh pretty awesome
not going to
lie
set looks super cool it does actually look quite
cool and hopefully fun to play
with okay clearly my coaster is intended to be a shuttle as
well I sense a theme running throughout this set
perhaps it's space shuttle related okay so there's card number one
uh multiple smaller
boxes does it have a motor this does not have a motor
um we're going to make it we're going to make it go
though we're going to make it have a motor actually I'm not
going to motorize the actual cars but uh we will push them
along in some kind of motorized
fashion
and why are your latest
videos uh about the New Year
I'm not sure what you're referring to there are you making any
oh hello from Georgia I assume are you making any personal changes
to it oh uh I'm just going to motorize this model I
will probably not make any modifications to the set itself well other
than sticking a motor on it but uh
which I guess is modification
enough all right we got two cars pretty
cool last one I'm going to guess this is going to look
very similar to the second
one but it will probably have some exhaust ports on it I
would guess oh yeah so
kind of engines in the
back uh when you're motorizing it be careful of the back there's
exhaust pieces with fire and mine fall off oh with the smallest
nudge Yeah well yeah we'll see we'll see
we we might have to the spaceship must might be going under
a lot of stress during the process of doing this so
we'll see if we have to modify or take off the engines
in the
back Oo we have a triple triple exhaust that's pretty
cool
oh yeah but I see these are just uh these pieces don't
have a full Hollow hole in them so we're only holding
them
by like the barest of
attachments so yeah that's a shame actually
oh yeah I know we're supposed to put these on yeah that'll
be better oh yeah that'll be good we put a 1 by
one round with a hole on top be a slightly better
connection oh and actually I stuck this tile on but that's not
we need a tail finan obviously oh yeah here we go
excellent
Tada and I assume we get to put some Minifigs in as
well
I guess they can sit in the middle okay here we
go I will get rid of my
instructions we will bring this front and center
first of all let's just see how this
[Music]
goes oh yeah nice nice nice and you see when it gets
to the this top here does uh it does trigger this
this [Music]
comet
okay so for
motorization let's see what we have going
on where do I keep my Lego yeah in collection behind me
okay okay I got some
pieces and we're going to try so the way I have envisioned
this is that we're going to mount some Wheels on the side
of the tracks similar to how they did in the first roller
coaster the first roller coaster has the the chain that brings the
roller coaster up but then at the top it uses some Wheels
to basically push it around the curves so we're going to do
something similar we're going to have
uh some Wheels mounted on the top and I
think we
will have two of them I do have a prototype already built
here oh I just lost the piece and we got some
Motors and a battery
box motor battery
box and I'm using these new flip-flop Technic gears which are Super
super awesome actually uh I think they're
uh going to be Game Changer in terms of building like compact
mechanisms so I think the way I want to do this the
way I had the Prototype I actually want two wheels mounted on
the side and I'm going to actually have two of these connect
together to
drive
so we need a way to drive these obviously and so we're
going to put some double bubble gears mounted like
so so we're going to go like
so
and we're actually just going to tack these
in like that that way I can drive and then we'll put
another one
obviously actually let's just make this all color
coordinated
put black one and then we need another
you know I took all these pieces out but oh there's
one okay
so now I have a single Drive drive axle that drives
both of those wheels so we're just going to have to we're
going to mount this on the side of the track here and
to do that I'm actually going to use the bars that run
in the middle of the track and we're just going to clip
we're going to use these uh little Clips with a bar on
them to clip clip it to the
track we're just going to stick that in a technic connector we're
going to put the Clips
in so that way I can clip this Technic connector to the
bottom of the track and then we can mount whatever
we want to to the track itself and it shouldn't interfere with
the coaster actually operating um so we'll make another
one of
those
and then we'll connect them together with a relatively long
axle so now I can clip it to basically because I have
these mounted on an axle I can adjust the length of them
to suit the distance between the crossbars on the track so
there we have a super it's actually quite a Sol
ID oh man I pulled a lot of these pieces out it's
quite a solid colle connection to the track just from underneath
and uh you can actually Mount this to because it's got a
sliding cuz these connectors are mounted on a sliding axle we can
sh vary the distance between them so we can actually mount it
to any track piece uh The Straits either of
these uh large slopes the small
slopes and uh I think we'll obviously probably have to figure out
a way to connect them to the curved slopes as well but
uh I don't think that should be too much of a
problem okay uh but now we need to
somehow Mount that as well so
more Technic connectors we're just going to slide these
on actually I'm going to sit this one in
there and I want this I don't want this to be rigidly
mounted so I'm actually sliding these wheels on these axles and I'm
going to stick a rubber band to pull them in so that
way when
the when the roller coaster comes by it can
actually uh it'll it needs to like basically have some flexibility
in the movement so that it doesn't bind uh so we're just
going to stick a rubber band on it like so so now
we have this basically spring-loaded set of Drive
wheels that we can mount beside the roller coaster
track and I think that's pretty much it for this one
I'm going to mount this
on so now in theory when the roller coaster comes up you
can see how it like turns the
wheels but if I'm actually driving these wheels it should lift the
coaster up now this coaster actually might be too heavy in my
testing I was only using empty coasters and this thing
is actually quite heavy so we'll see it might not work at
all oh and actually her head gets in the way very interesting
I might have to mount it on the other side so there's
clearance which we can definitely do shouldn't be a
problem and then we should have some
clearance
okay uh now we need to make another one of those actually
we're going to need to make a few might need to make
more
than more than a
few
we're going to need at least three because we'll probably need one
on this section of track one on this section of track and
then one on this section of track so I'm just going to
put a bunch together I think I have enough I think I
pull enough pieces out to
make three of
them or four of them I have uh one prototype already bu
built
so but now that I know how this goes together should be
pretty uh
quick kind of doing this just based on memory but uh when
first starting with an idea do you prototype just by taking Parts
in building or do you do anything electronically first no it's all
just mostly I'd say 90 9% of the time
I always start with real bricks and I just figure
out how to put them together yeah I just prototype with real
bricks
it's definitely the way I prefer to
build okay we need to make the drives train
again uh maybe mount it on the other side to avoid collision
with train below yeah since the gears are hanging too low yes
great minds think
alike indeed that is what we have
done okay
uh actually I don't know if I have enough of
that
part
all right there number
two oh yeah we do do some Mi mix and
match the colors but that's
fine
okay actually one of
these actually I'm just going to put two together for now for
the for the Straits
[Music] which way do I want this to
go this
way I need more half p
riveting entertainment
here do I have a mechanical engineering degree or is it just
experience uh I do have an engineering degree it's uh not mechanical
though okay uh
basically all of this is just from experience and playing okay I'm
going to mount these oh actually yeah I want those on the
other
side I want to mount it on the other side M
this one on the other side as well if there's space
yeah appears to be
space and then we somehow need to motorize all
this and uh for that
actually I'm going to need to get a few more
pieces oh basically I'm going to try
Mount the motor directly onto the end of one of them so
we can drive it give it a little direct drive
action um and there appears to be more room at top so
I'm just going to take the top one off and we're going
to stick a motor on it
somehow and for now I'm just going to tack on
I'm just going to tack
on I'm going to tack on a motor we're just going to
tack on a lift arm to the end so we have
something to actually connect the motor to and we're actually going to
need a longer axle which I anticipated so we'll get
a five long axle
we'll stick this
on so this way basically I've just stuck another Technic connector
on here so I can put a pin on it and then
we can just stick the motor right on So in theory we
got our battery
box stick it on we
can just direct drive this whole
thing let's see except it is on the other
side will this fit down here actually I think we'll put it
on the bottom if we
can will this all fit
it would be nicer if there wasn't a big motor sticking out
the top
anyway well this slope is just a bit in the way so
I'm actually going to take that off for
now okay so we have a motor
with one
motorized it's hitting it's hitting the
alien okay there we go so now in
theory we got one motor in theory when this comes up here
oh it's going the wrong
way oh yeah it pushes pushes the coaster up
which is good but obviously we need to need to motorize the
other section as
well I love your GBC modules I plans for new one hey
guys let's start cheers thanks my
friend Lego Battle Master just joined you're almost done yeah we're almost
done uh well I don't know if it'll completely work when we're
but anyway okay uh yeah we're getting we're getting places we have
one motorized section to track uh we do need to somehow transfer
all this rotational movement to this other motorized section of track
or other so I'm going to put this one back on and
in
theory I think we can we can just connect
these two axles with some universal
joints which I conveniently have located
here how far how long an axle do we
need actually let's slide this down a little
bit these are adjustable to a certain
degree because you can just slide them on an
axle but I do think I want a nine long
axle instead of an eight long
one
let's slide that back up okay so now in theory that should
drive both of
them oh except have the gearing backwards on
this one this one has to be turned
around
right much better oh yeah now we need a shorter axle
back it's important that the gears go the right way otherwise
your roller coaster is going nowhere
fast
okay now we're
cooking both Motors going in the right direction
excellent crazy Technic with all kinds of stuff in the chat I
have no idea what you're talking
about
I think he need some support from the motor itself at the
bottom it will hang and wiggle in the whole assembly due to
vibration yeah we'll see I
mean so far so good
uh we're just going to do some manual testing up to this
[Music] point now my coaster is not on the track
so help [Music]
oh yeah it does seem to be a bit too
heavy well that work oh
[Music]
yeah okay but now we also need to
motorize we need more we need more
power we definitely need more have this other one pre-built
here which we can
mount on the outside of this track
and I think like ultimately you might be able to join all
of these uh accelerators together with
the you know universal joints but uh that's going to probably be
super annoying and really finicky to get working so for now I'm
just going
to that is definitely running the wrong way we're going to need
to reverse these as well if I use the same battery box
anyway it's also missing a gear so that needs to
be rectified
it's going quite fast
yeah uh but I will need
to
actually I might just get another do I have another battery box
no probably not because I'll need
to change the gearing well maybe I can just turn this
around
okay will
this no because I turned it around and I turned the gearing
around I actually just need to [Music]
redo the gearing on this one
oh no I lost the
piece
can you make breaks for the station too yeah I don't think
so
I think ultimately I need to put the gears on the other
side in this configur I just need to drive it from the
back actually so what we're going to do is
we are going to make that
longer need a longer lift
arm and then this axle will need to be
1 2 3 four five six 7even
long
and
then yeah there we
go
excellent so in theory I still think this coaster
might be a bit too
[Music] heavy a it doesn't quite make it to the
first set of
drivers I'm just going to try it with a
empty coaster I'm just
curious
yeah cuzz with a lighter coaster it actually makes it all the
way to [Music]
[Music]
the it's hard to tell what the dark blue on the dark
blue but
uh
this is what happens when you're trying to put prototypes into
production I'm actually just going to going to confirm that it's just
the weight that's an issue I'm going to use these cars without
decorations
oh interesting these ones definitely don't run as smooth as the ones
I
[Music]
have got to trim some fat off those astronauts oh Jake sovich
is in the
house yeah clearly uh
it's uh I mean we could definitely add another accelerator
to this track piece
here which we might have to
do to make it more
reliable but yeah it is definitely an intense ride
oh we're close though it's definitely close I'll definitely have to play
around with it a little bit
more I think if you have a standard track with the without
the curved without the curved slope Corners
uh you could definitely get a little bit better
performance out of it
um
or at least you wouldn't need as many Motors I'm actually going
to mount this a little bit differently seems to Sag quite a
bit and I think some of the spacing could probably be improved
a little
bit oh almost made
it it's interesting that my this
coaster for whatever reason seems [Music]
to seems to work much
[Music]
better
can't you put the wheels on the bottom of the tracks that
we're a little bit less visible yeah no not
[Music]
really please please please make the stream available to watch later yeah
I think most of my streams are public I mean some of
them aren't but
uh some fold of P paper under table
legs oh yeah it' be really cool if you make it bigger
with a
loop looks like the comet may slow just ha yeah I took
the Comet off um it definitely runs a lot smoother with the
Comet
off and I think
uh some improvement could be made to the mounting
yeah like we just need the wheels to be just a tad
closer to the [Music]
rails I mean I think if you were making a bigger coaster
you would just use the TR the train uh the train you
would just use the chain system I think the nice thing about
this particular system is that uh
you know it's a relatively low piece count it's easy to just
tack it on so even if if you just have a really
small almost flat Loop in like a City layout or something
uh you could easily just like stick this on and your you
know your your tram could just run on its
own I mean obviously it won't work for like super large uh
coaster layouts um unless you put multi them multiple
of them around the entire track but uh
[Music]
but uh I mean it is pretty fun to watch anyway it's
a bit loud obviously anything with motors is loud
uh but uh yeah anyway uh that's pretty much all
I wanted to do today obviously it could use some improvement but
this is why we test things out uh we get some feedback
obviously it needs to handle heavier cars uh a little bit better
which I think it can do obviously the heavier cars just don't
make it up this slope so we need another we would need
another accelerator here which is actually quite a lot for just this
small set um I think some of the older sets like the
the pirate coaster uh you would only need two accelerators cuz you
just have the one big hill
uh which should should be good as long as it can make
it up to the as long as the front of the car
can make it back up to the first accelerator
um but uh yeah we'll see again we'll just have to test
it out but I'm looking forward to testing this with different track
configurations you know just to see what uh you know what works
and what doesn't and uh that's just all part of the process
of developing any kind of new system like this
uh so yeah but I think that's probably all we'll do today
I'll probably ask see what's going on the chat before I sign
off but uh it's definitely lunch time for me uh when you
put the motor in the corner a bit more into the corner
yeah I mean you can definitely Mount these well actually yeah I
can just try that like I can just Mount this one lower
well actually I can because for whatever reason the Center Bar is
thicker than the rest
um I mean actually I can I'll just move that here and
then use these two
uh yeah we we Mount this closer to the corner I mean
it's definitely more stable if we mount it in the middle
but I just don't know if we Mount this further like it
might pick it up but I don't know if it'll push it
enough to get to the next one now it's got to be
is a fine balance between
being oh yeah with it's like for a heavier car might not
oh there we
go good idea
uh but I still think for the heavier
car it might have some issues
oh yeah see it doesn't
quite oh yeah yeah yeah okay okay
[Music]
okay put the whole the kids would puke days yeah
it's obviously uh way too intense for small
children
yeah unfortunately that mounting doesn't quite work as well uh so that
goes with the so let's add
like Yeah we're definitely getting into the hanger Zone but let's add
let's put some bricks on one
car
[Music]
okay we're still work we're still working we're still working I think
uh as I mentioned yeah we need to adjust the mounting just
so it's a little bit
more uh it just needs to be bit more snug to the
rails to really pick up the vehicles really pick up the
[Music]
cars yeah we're getting a little bit heavier
now it's not quite making it all the way and I think
if we add the weight on this one it might be a
bit too [Music]
much yeah doesn't quite make
it couldn't you add a support underneath the wheels to make more
stable yeah we definitely can uh
I'm also curious I've never tried it with like multiple
cars like how many cars can we get going on
[Music] here
interesting
I mean that works pretty well too
uh I mean nobody wants a roller coaster with three cars on
it uh seems very
uh it seems uh not very entertaining uh
maybe an extra car for length though that will add weight yeah
well obviously again great minds think a like if you make it
a little bigger would be better
yeah only one booster seems to be needed to be hanging other
can be supported from the bottom yeah uh I mean there are
definitely lots of ways to mount the wheels uh
my experiment was just uh trying to make it as flexible
as possible because mounting it to the to the track themselves
means that like you don't have to build up any kind of
sub substructure to to mount each one individually like the mounting can
be the same for every one and it doesn't matter like where
your track is relative to wherever your base is it could be
like raised up up
higher so that was a logic behind mounting them to the track
itself just makes it a lot more flexible um
and then you can mount it to standard straight pieces as
well attach two TRS together
yeah uh fill the whole track with cars actually if you filled
the whole track with cars you probably only need one accelerator to
keep the whole thing going but I actually actually don't know if
I have actually I probably do have that many track cars but
oh actually probably not I think I only have like 25 of
these it would be
insane but what's the point of having a live stream if you
don't do crazy things so here we go how many of these
can we put
together before it all collapses it why don't these go together before
it collapses in a
heap oh my God for whatever these ones
are okay so clearly
a super long train doesn't seem
to all right how how far can we go
oh my God some of these are like really hard to put
together okay clearly I have uh an actual ton of these
cars which is a bit
ridiculous I think we bought these in plug bulk like the first
time they were available which seems ridiculous to me like who needs
like a million train cars but you know whatever clearly
I needed a lot for
this
actually definitely works a lot better with longer cars because uh you
definitely have uh
more basically a car is always in contact with one of the
driving
[Applause] Wheels well why stop now we'll just get all the ones
I have
Legos in motion hey fellow YouTuber I just got here what's going
on well you just missed a a lot of building
roller
coasters now we're building a snake coaster oh man
do I have enough to actually complete the complete the
snake oh yeah I do for
sure oh but the spacing okay we're actually just going to run
it like this
first
yeah I can't actually connect them together because as you can probably
I don't know if you can tell but well I guess there's
a lot of flexibility in the the
spacing so like depending on where it is in the
track I guess I can connect
together there we go
connected actually I'm just really curious if I just drop I don't
think we need as many accelerators
now definitely doesn't run as well [Music]
though he definitely helps to have more
power yeah maybe you can make that into Dragon I mean it
does kind of look ridiculously awesome if these cars were all decorated
in some way with like uh yeah some crazy
snake eating itself you know snake eating the tail even
just having like a
circular
track the snake eating its own tail that would be pretty interesting
uh looks like a bicycle chain maybe you could make that but
with a dragon yeah reminds me of the conveyors in Amazon warehouse
yeah
the common roller closer to Legoland yeah like the classic snake
game uh yeah anyway that actually turned out to be super
fun but I think we are probably good to go I definitely
need to eat lunch now
uh oh actually I was curious I'm just going to count these
1 2 3 4 5 8 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 16 17 18 19 20 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 9 10 11 12 33
cars so yeah it's crazy and I have three more so I
have 36 in total actually I might have a few more in
some other Coaster sets that I haven't opened yet but uh that's
all I have kicking
around actually I should have another one of these too actually so
who knows 36 plus okay anyway
that is it for today thanks for the entertaining stream and the
cool experiment suggestions at the end it actually turned out to be
pretty good and very entertaining uh
hope everybody has a good day hope everybody has a good holidays
actually I'll probably stream next week I think I don't know what
we'll do actually I think I might uh try to make the
ski hill bigger uh I might try and extend it we'll see
how big we can make the ski hill and still have it
actually work um cuz I a few people have requested to see
how how big it could go uh anyway thanks for everybody for
joining thanks R Hamburg as always for moderating uh thanks everybody for
the questions and suggestions uh hopefully you all had
as much fun as I did and we will see you next
week keep on building thanks for watching see you next time